Krystal receives a request to execute Vajram V1.
The request contains the values of all the input facets of V1.
V1 is ready for execution.
V1 depends on vajrams V2, V3, and V4 in sequential order,
i.e V3 waits for V2 and V4 waits for V3.
V1 constructs the request for V2 containing values for V2's input facets.
This is called input resolution.
V2 is ready for execution.
V2 depends on vajrams V5 and V6 parallely (V5 and V6 do not need to wait for each other).
V2 constructs the requests for V5 and V6 which are then ready for execution.
V5 and V6 do not have dependencies.
They start execution concurrently.
V5 and V6 finish execution independently after some time.
All of V2's dependencies are now completed.
V2 starts execution.
V2 finishes execution after some time.
The first dependency facet of V1 is now completed.
V2 now has enough information to resolve the inputs of V3.
V3 is ready for execution.
V3 has a sequential dependency on V7 and V8.
V3 resolves V7's inputs. V7 is ready for execution.
V7 has no dependencies.
V7 is decorated with a 'Retrying decorator'.
V7 starts execution.
V7 fails with an error.
V7's response is intercepted by the Retrying decorator.
which is configured to retry thrice on error.
V7 is retried by the decorator (invisibly to V3).
V7 starts executing for the second time.
V7 fails again.
The response is intercepted by the retrying decorator again.
V7 is retried for a second time.
V7 starts executing for the third time.
V7 succeeds on this attempt.
V3's first dependency facet is now completed.
V3 resolves the inputs of its second dependency V8.
V8 is ready for execution.
V8 has no dependencies and is decorated by a caching decorator.
V8 starts execution.
V8 succeeds.
V8's response is intercepted by the caching decorator.
The response is cached with the input facets values of V8 as key.
All of V3's facets are compeleted.
V3 starts execution.
V3 succeeds.
V1's second facet is now compeleted.
V1 now resolves the inputs for V4.
V4 is ready for execution.
V4 has a sequential dependency on V8 and V9.
V4 resolves the inputs for V8.
The caching decorator of V8 intercepts the request and looks up the cache.
There is a cache hit. The response is made available to V4 without executing V8 again.
V4 uses the result of V8 to resolve the inputs for V9.
V9 is ready for execution.
V9 has no dependencies.
V9 starts execution.
V9 succeeds.
All of V4's facets are now completed.
V4 starts execution.
V4 fails with an error.
The third dependency facet of V1 has failed.
But V4 is an optional dependency of V1.
V1 handles the error of V4, and continues execution.
V1 succeeds.
The platform returns the result of V1 to the original caller.